Finding Aid for Democratic Party of Michigan records, 1932-2008
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Visual Materials
  - Biographies / Photographs of Political Figures 1965-1975
    - State Senators
      - Faust, William (Box 93)
      - Hart, Jerome T. (Box 93)
      - Hertel, John (Box 93)
      - Holmes, David (Box 93)
      - Mack, Joseph S. (Box 93)
      - O'Brien, Michael (Box 93)
    - State Representatives
      - Albosta, Donald (Box 93)
      - Bennett, John (Box 93)
      - Bonior, David E. (Box 93)
      - Bullard, Perry (Box 93)
      - Clodfelter, Mark (Box 93)
      - Crim, Bobby (Box 93)
      - DiNello, Gilbert (Box 93)
      - Edwards, George (Box 93)
      - Elliott, Daisy (Box 93)
      - Faxon, Jack (Box 93)
      - Forbes, Joseph (Box 93)
      - Geralds, Monte (Box 93)
      - Goemaere, Warren (Box 93)
      - Griffin, Michael (Box 93)
      - Hasper, Gerrit C. (Box 93)
      - Hellman, Russell (Box 93)
      - Holcomb, Tom (Box 93)
      - Hollister, David (Box 93)
      - Huffman, Bill S. (Box 93)
      - Jacobetti, Dominic (Box 93)
      - Jondahl, H. Lynn (Box 93)
      - Kehres, Raymond C. (Box 93)
      - Keith, William (Box 93)
      - Kelsey, John T. (Box 93)
      - Kildee, Dale (Box 93)
      - McCollough, Lucille H. (Box 93)
      - McNeely, Matthew (Box 93)
      - Mastin, Philip (Box 93)
      - Monsma, Stephen (Box 93)
      - Montgomery, George (Box 93)
      - Montgomery, George F. (Box 93)
      - O'Neill, James E., Jr. (Box 93)
      - Owen, Gary M. (Box 93)
      - Rocca, Sal (Box 93)
      - Rosenbaum, Paul (Box 93)
      - Scott, Harold J. (Box 93)
      - Spaniola, Francis R. (Box 93)
      - Stopcyzinski, Steven (Box 93)
      - Stopcyzinski, Thaddeus C. (Box 93)
      - Trim, Claude (Box 93)
      - Wierzbicki, Frank V. (Box 93)
      - Wolpe, Howard (Box 93)
      - Young, Joseph (Box 93)
      - Young, Richard A. (Box 93)
    - United States Congress
      - Carr, M. Robert (Box 93)
      - Conyers, John, Jr. (Box 93)
      - Dingell, John D. (Box 93)
      - Ford, William D. (Box 93)
      - Kildee, Dale (Box 93)
      - Staebler, Neil (Box 93)
      - Traxler, Robert (Box 93)
      - VanderVeen, Richard (Box 93)
      - Riegle, Don (Box 93)
  - Videotapes, U-matic
    - 1989 Jefferson-Jackson Day Dinner, April 3, 1989, 5 videotapes U-matic (Box 94)
    - Coleman Young, probably speaking at 1989 Jefferson-Jackson Day Dinner, April 3, 1989, 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 94)
    - Yokich and Kennedy probably speaking at 1989 Jefferson-Jackson Day Dinner, April 3, 1989, 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 94)
    - "Reach for the Stars" (Democratic Party Fund Raiser May 8, 1989, 1 reels; 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 94)
    - Presidential Selection in Michigan (with Rick Weiner, guest), 29 min; 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 94)
    - Michigan Democratic Party Platform, 4:11 min.; 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 94)
    - Michigan Democratic Party, Westin Hotel, Detroit March 12, 1994, 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 94)
    - Untitled, audio layoffs, 2 cuts., 1 videotapes U-matic (Box 94)
  - Videotapes, VHS
    - 1990 campaign videotapes, 1989-1990, 6 tapes (Box 95)
    - "Focus on Youth" October 15, 1989, 20:40 (Box 95)
    - State of State, Democratic Perspective 1991, 24:00 (Box 95)
    - U.P. Jeff-Jack Dinner undated (Box 95)
    - Redistricting Michigan 1992 (Box 95)
    - Michigan Democratic Party and Democratic Campaign Committee October 22, 1982 (Box 95)
      (5 30 sec. campaign spots)
  - Motion pictures
    - "Telethon" undated, 1 reels 4 3/4-inch (Box 95)
    - Michigan Democratic Committee June 5, 1968, 2 reels (in 1 canister) (Box 95)
    - Hubert Humphrey promotional film from the 1968 presidential campaign, 12 in. reel
- Sound Recordings
  The Sound Recordings series include recordings, May-Sept. 1963, of "Platform," a radio program produced by the Michigan Democratic Party. There are also recordings of state party conventions, 1972, 1973 and 1975; speeches of Hubert Humphrey and other party promotions produced during the 1968 campaign; and miscellaneous tapes of conferences and meetings, and political announcements.
  - Radio program "Platform" presented by Michigan Democratic Party, each reel is 7 in. and plays at 7 1/2 ips
    - State Insurance Commissioner Sherwood Colburn on health insurance; Philip Hart on civil rights legislation; Zolton Ferency on Con-Con recount; John B. Swainson on 1964 issues. May 26, 1963 (Box 96)
      (tape 1)
    - Stuart Hertzberg? (party finance chairman); Sen. Patrick McNamara on equal pay for women; Mildred Jeffrey on youth employment; review of recount. June 2, 1963 (Box 96)
      (tape 2)
    - Tom Downs on changes in election law; Joseph A. Gillis on congressional redistricting; miscellaneous party news. June 9, 1963 (Box 96)
      (tape 3)
    - Roy Stevens on implication of changes in state taxation to Detroit school system; James G. O'Hara on sugar; and comments on commercial endorsements. June 23, 1963 (Box 96)
      (tape 4)
    - William Patrick and Zolton Ferency discussing equal rights in Michigan. July 7, 1963 (Box 96)
      (tape 5)
    - John Dingell on domestic peace corps; Billie Farnum on policing public funds; and governor's conference. July 28, 1963 (Box 96)
      (tape 6)
    - Lucien Nedzi on civil defense legislation and other Congressional legislation; James M. Hare on automobile inspections; also discussion on fiscal reform. August 4, 1963 (Box 96)
      (tape 7)
    - Averill Harriman and Philip A. Hart on test ban treaty; and Norman Crandall, director of special projects division of the Democratic Party of Michigan. August 11, 1963 (Box 96)
      (tape 8)
    - Neil Staebler and Adelaide Hart; also interim party financial report. August 18, 1963 (Box 96)
      (tape 9)
    - Damon Keith on civil rights; and Norman Crandall, director of special projects division of the Democratic Party of Michigan. September 1, 1963 (Box 96)
      (tape 10)
    - Joseph Cargal (?), publisher of Hamtramck Citizen and Ben Nathanson, publisher of East Side Shopper talk about prospects of Democratic Party. September 8, 1963 (Box 96)
      (tape 11)
    - Philip Hart discusses foreign aid with Walt W. Rostow; William Ford, and Charles Towner; and remarks on proposed tax reform program September 15, 1963 (Box 96)
      (tape 12)
    - David Levinbaum (?), Wayne County Democratic Chairman on Detroit open housing ordinance; Barbara Streisand; discussion of survey. September 22, 1963 (Box 96)
      (tape 13)
    - State representative James Karoub of Highland Park discussing tax on beer and breweries; also discussion of tax reform. September 29, 1963 (Box 96)
      (tape 14)
    - Conversation with a young man concerning his interest in the Democratic Party (probably from Platform program). Undated. (3 in. reel) (Box 96)
      (tape 15)
  - Recording of State Democratic Conventions
    - Recording undated of Democratic convention, 1 audiotapes 3 3/4 ips; 7 inches; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 96)
      (tape 16)
    - Recording June 11, 1972 of Democratic Convention, Cobo Hall, 2 audiotapes 3 3/4 ips; 7 inches; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 96)
      (reel 1 of 3 reels missing)
      (tapes 17-18)
    - Recording August 27, 1972 of Democratic State Convention., 5 audiotapes dual track; 7 1/2 ips; 7 inches; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 96)
      (tapes 19-23)
    - Recording February 4, 1973 of Democratic Convention, Cobo Hall., 4 audiotapes 3 3/4 ips; 7 inches; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 96)
      (tapes 24-27)
    - Recording January 26, 1975 of Democratic Convention., 2 audiotapes 3 3/4 ips; 7 inches; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 96)
      (tapes 28-29)
  - Miscellaneous reel-to-reel tapes
    - Unidentified Democratic conference undated, 5 inches and 7 inches; 5 audiotapes 3 3/4 ips; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 96)
      (tapes 30-35)
    - Economic conference July 17-18, 1959, 2 audiotapes dual track; 3 3/4 ips; 7 inches; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 97)
      (tapes 36-37)
    - Recording of Ken Hylton's apportionment hearings, Detroit, Mich., 1 audiotapes 3 3/4 ips; 7 inches; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 97)
      (tape 38)
    - Television program of WJIM, Governor's News Conference, featuring Governor William Milliken undated, 1 audiotapes 7 1/2 ips; 7 inches; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 97)
      (tape 39)
    - Recording March-April 1968 featuring in part President Lyndon Johnson on Public Affairs News (Democratic Party program) (in part test tape); also discussion of 1968 election campaign., 1 sound tape reel: and 7 1/2 ips; 3 3/4 ips (Box 97)
      (tape 40)
    - Interview circa 1970 with Fred Harris, chairman of the Democratic National Committee., 1 audiotapes; 7 1/2 ips; 5 inches; reel-to-reel tapes 13:26 (Box 97)
      (tape 41)
    - Promotion for Democratic Party telethon 1968, 1 audiotapes 7 1/2 ips; 3 inches; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 97)
      (tape 42)
    - Recording circa 1972 of state senator Sander Levin discussing proposed stadium for downtown Detroit., 1 audiotapes 2 min.; 7 1/2 ips; 5 inches; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 97)
      (tape 43)
    - Talk 1969 of Philip A. Hart, concerning military expenditures., 1 audiotapes 2 min.; 7 1/2 ips; 2 inches; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 97)
      (tape 44)
    - Discussion 1972 by James McNeely, Democratic state chairman, concerning regional party conference in Iron Mountain, Michigan., 1 audiotapes 7 1/2 ips; 5 inches; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 97)
      (tape 45)
    - Interview 1968 with Hubert Humphrey concerning the issues of the 1968 campaign., 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes (Box 97)
      (tape 46)
    - Speech July 1968 of Hubert Humphrey concerning Democracy and Human Rights., 1 audiotapes 7 1/2 ips; 5 inches; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 97)
      (tape 47)
    - Speech April 1968 of Hubert Humphrey, entitled "Freedom's Business", 1 audiotapes 7 1/2 ips; 5 inches; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 97)
      (tape 48)
    - Speeches 1968 of Hubert Humphrey, consisting of fragments of campaign speeches., 1 audiotapes 7 1/2 ips; 7 inches; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 97)
      (tape 49)
    - Remarks 1968 by Hubert Humphrey, and Secretary of Defense Clark Clifford for program, Public Affairs News., 1 audiotapes 7 1/2 ips; 7 inches; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 97)
      (tape 50)
    - Recording 1968 of Einar Erlandsen concerning the income tax and schools; and Gary Frink challenging his opponent to debates., 1 audiotapes 7 1/2 ips; 5 inches; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 97)
      (tape 51)
    - Talk, undated, of unidentified individual concerning school busing., 1 audiotapes 7 1/2 ips; 2 inches; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 97)
      (tape 52)
    - Unidentified., 7 inches and 2 inches; 2 audiotapes 3 3/4 ips; reel-to-reel tapes (Box 97)
      (tapes 53-54)
    - Democratic Party of Michigan, Tape #1, Senator Hart February 21, 1964 (Box 97)
      (tape 55)
    - State Democratic Convention February 17-18, 1979 Detroit, Cobo, 3 tapes (Box 97)
      (tape 56, 57, 58)
    - Michigan Democratic Convention August 26, 1984, 4 tapes (Box 97)
      (tape 59, 60, 61, 62)
    - Johnson, version 2 October 26, 1992 (Box 97)
      (tape 63)
    - Democratic National Committee, Families October 28, 1992 (Box 97)
      (tape 64)
    - Undated, Youth Voter Registration PSA's (Box 97)
      (tape 65)
    - Undated, Democratic Tax Program, 7 1/2 ips (Box 97)
      (tape 66)
    - Undated, Jeff Jack Master (Box 97)
      (tape 67)
    - Undated, 2 tapes (Box 97)
      (tape 68, 69)
  - Cassette Tapes
    - Meeting of Democratic State Central Committee, Escanaba, Mich. July 21, 1973, 2 audiocassettes (Box 98)
    - Public hearings re. energy and nuclear power circa 1975, 4 audiocassettes (Box 98)
    - Recording July 8, 1971 of Democratic apportionment Committee caucus., 2 audiocassettes (Box 98)
    - Recording October 1971 of unidentified man concerning Democratic politics., 1 audiocassettes (Box 98)
    - Democratic National Committee, Radio Commercials 1982, 1 audiocassettes (Box 98)
    - Democratic State Central Committee June 20, 1981, 1 audiocassettes (Box 98)
    - Frank Lindsley (Democratic Policy Committee) speaking on mass transit circa 1973, 1 audiocassettes (Box 98)